One Pace Premium Keep the project alive: ko-fi.com/not6ip
One Pace Premium Keep the project alive: ko-fi.com/not6ip
25 Years Ago
‫قبل 25 عامًا‬
Turn back the clock twenty-five years...
‫سنعود للماضي قبل 25 عامًا...‬
Shortly before the dawn of the Great Pirate Era...
‫بُعيد بدء عصر القراصنة العظيم...‬
Are you louts enjoyin' yourselves?!
‫هل يستمتع الجميع بوقتهم؟!‬
I am glad I accompanied you...
‫أنا سعيدٌ لأنّني تبعتك،‬
Roger!
‫يا روجر!‬
Huh?! What's gotten into you, idiot?!
‫ماذا؟! لماذا تقول شيئًا كهذا الآن أيّها الأحمق؟!‬
Oden!
‫أودين!‬
We should be thanking you!
‫بل أنت من يستحق شكرنا!‬
You're drinking too much, Roger!
‫أنت تفرط في الشراب! تمالك نفسك!‬
Shut it!
‫اخرس! لن أقبل نصائح من طبيب ثمل!‬
I'm concerned about your health!
‫أنا قلق حيال صحّتك!‬
You bastard!
‫أيّها الوغد!‬
That's how you cure stupidity.
‫كان ذلك علاجًا للغباء.‬
Shut your trap!
‫اخرس!‬
Damn you!
‫سُحقًا لك!‬
I must go back...
‫عليّ العودة...‬
To Wano?
‫إلى بلاد وانو؟‬
Yes.
‫نعم، ما زال هنالك أمر مهمّ لإنجازه...‬
Is there anything we can do to help, Oden?
‫أهنالك ما بوسعنا مساعدتك فيه يا أودين؟‬
If you need a hand...
‫إن احتجت ليد العون...‬
I don't mind lending you one, Oden!
‫فأستطيع تقديمها لك يا أودين-سان!‬
You dummy!
‫أيها الغبيّ! ستكون عقبة في طريقه فحسب!‬
Hey, Oden! I'm sure I could help!
‫اسمع يا أودين-سان، أنا واثق أنّ بإمكاني المساعدة!‬
Rayleigh...
‫ريلي...‬
Redtaro and Buggyjiro...
‫أحمرتارو، باغيجيرو...‬
You have my thanks!
‫شكرًا لكم!‬
However...
‫لكن...‬
this duty lies with the Kozuki alone.
‫يقع هذا على عاتقنا نحن عشيرة الكوزكي!‬
I've asked so many times, why am I "jiro" as if I'm the second son?
‫كم مرّة طلبت منك ألاّ تناديني بجيرو كأنني الابن الثاني؟‬
Let it go!
‫لا تلقِ بالًا للأمر!‬
Gotcha. The Kozuki, huh?
‫صحيح. عشيرة الكوزكي؟‬
I learned much throughout this voyage...
‫تعلّمت الكثير خلال هذه الرّحلة...‬
I had always wondered why Wano closed its doors.
‫تساءلت دائمًا لماذا أغلقت بلاد وانو أبوابها،‬
I left imprudently,
‫كانت مغادرتي للبلاد خياري، لذلك لن أقول شيئًا أنانيًّا مثل «دعوني أصبح الشّوغن...»‬
But I must pass on my will at any cost!
‫لكن عليّ توريث هذه العزيمة مهما كلّف الأمر!‬
With the aid of my exceptional retainers that I left behind,
‫برفقة خدمي العظماء الّذين تركتهم خلفي،‬
I will open the borders of Wano,
‫سأفتح بلاد وانو!‬
and I shall await a future that will come more than twenty years from now!
‫وسأنتظر «المستقبل» الّذي سيحلّ بعد أكثر من عشرين عامًا من الآن!‬
Let's do it, Oden!
‫لننجز الأمر يا أودين!‬
Yes!
‫أجل!‬
We shall, Roger!
‫لننجز الأمر يا روجر!‬
Now, twenty-five years have passed.
‫والآن قد مرّ على ذلك 25 عامًا.‬
25 Years Later
‫بعد 25 سنة‬
Act 3 Wano
‫لبلاد وانو‬ ‫الفصل الثالث‬
What a perfect day for a banquet.
‫إنه يومٌ مثالي لإقامة مأدبة.‬
The weather itself even favors our lord, Orochi.
‫حتّى الطّقس يصبّ في مصلحة أوروتشي-ساما.‬
This year, Kyoshiro is remaining to supervise the capital.
‫هذه المرّة سيظلّ كيوشيرو في العاصمة كي يهتم بها! أخبره أنّنا نعتمد عليه!‬
Yes, sir!
‫حاضر!‬
Poor guy!
‫مثير للشفقة! لا يستطيع حضور المأدبة!‬
Habu Port in Hakumai is known as the largest port in Wano.
‫يُعرف ميناء هابو هذا والذي في هاكوماي بأنه الميناء الأكبر في بلاد وانو.‬
Maple trees line the giant pier which projects from the shore into the sea,
‫تصطفّ أشجار القيقب على طول الرّصيف الضّخم من السّاحل وصولًا إلى البحر،‬
and the lovely scene of fluttering red leaves sends ships off.
‫والمشهد الخلاّب للأوراق الحمراء المتطايرة وهي تودّع السّفن.‬
It's a wonderful day!
‫إنّه يوم رائع!‬
Fetch some sake! Let's have a cup while admiring those red leaves!
‫أحضروا السّاكي! لنحتسِ كوبًا ونحن نبدي إعجابنا بهذه الأوراق الحمراء!‬
Lord Orochi, you should abstain until we reach Lord Kaido...
‫يا أوروتشي-ساما، لا يجدر بك الشّرب إلى أن تقابل كايدو-ساما...‬
Who cares?! I'm sure he's already drunk, too!
‫ومن يهتمّ؟! أنا واثق أنّه ثمل أيضًا!‬
It's a massive banquet with 30,000 attendees!
‫إنّها مأدبة ضخمة يحضرها 30 ألف ضيف! لنستمتع كما جرت العادة!‬
Once a year, on the night of the Fire Festival,
‫في ليلة مهرجان النّار السّنويّ،‬
the two leaders who rule over Wano come together at Onigashima.
‫يلتقي القائدان اللذان يقفان على رأس بلاد وانو في أونيغاشيما‬
They throw a huge banquet for the combined armies of Orochi and Kaido.
‫ويقيمان مأدبة ضخمة يجتمع فيها كلٌّ من جيش أوروتشي وجيش كايدو‬
Open up the borderless map, then
‫استهل قراءة الخريطة التي لا حدود لها‬
Head for that unknown edge of the ocean
‫انطلق نحو المكان الذي لا نهاية له‬
LET’S SAIL ON right now, hoist your sails up high
‫لنبحر للأمام ونرفع تلك الأشرعة‬
Riding on the wind
‫الحق بالرياح‬
DON’T GIVE UP, it’s time to finish what we started
‫لا تستسلم ما دمت عازمًا‬
So don't you grow disheartened
‫فلا عودة للوراء‬
Laugh the tears away through the storm
‫سنواجه المياه المتقلبة بضحكاتنا‬
SHOUT IT OUT, when you feel down always remember
‫اصرخ لحماية عزيمتك من الانكسار‬
That’s what your friends are there for
‫فرفاقك يقفون إلى جانبك‬
Y’know there’s no point in fronting,
‫ليس عليك التظاهر بالقوة أبدًا‬
Even in the face of utter darkness
‫ولو حاولت الظلمة أن تنال من صميمك‬
C’mon, BRAVE IT OUT We’ll be alright
‫هيا، تشجع‬
Together you know that we’ll never lose a fight
‫فالروابط الثابتة باقية‬
Open up the borderless map, then
‫استهل قراءة الخريطة التي لا حدود لها‬
Head for that unknown edge of the ocean
‫انطلق نحو المكان الذي لا نهاية له‬
All great journeys starts with a single step
‫كن جسورًا لتخطو خطوة للأمام‬
DREAMIN’ ON
‫تمسّك بالحُلم‬
Open up the borderless map, then
‫استهل قراءة الخريطة التي لا حدود لها‬
Raise the flag we swore to defend
‫تلك الراية برهان على نذرنا‬
We’ll never stop until we’ve reached the top
‫تواصل النضال‬
Just be true to yourself until the end
‫فابقَ مخلصًا لجوهرك‬
Set sail and grab it, DREAMIN ON
‫تمسك بالحلم وداوم عليه‬
Flower Capital
‫عاصمة‬ ‫الزهور‬
The Day of the Fire Festival
‫في‬ ‫يوم‬ ‫مهرجان‬ ‫النار‬
The Designated Port
‫الميناء الموعود‬
Drink up! Drink up!
‫اشربوا! اشربوا!‬
Come on! Dance!
‫هيّا! لنرقص!‬
Drink! Sing!
‫اشربوا! غنّوا!‬
It's the Fire Festival in the capital today!
‫اليوم هو يوم مهرجان النّار في العاصمة!‬
It's the one day a year we're allowed to drink!
‫اليوم الوحيد المسموح لنا بالشّرب فيه!‬
Let's really drink hard and let loose today!
‫سنشرب حتّى الشّبع ونحظى بأفضل الأوقات اليوم!‬
Hurry up! It's already started!
‫هيا، أسرعي فقد بدأ الاحتفال سلفًا!‬
Hold on! I can't get my bangs to behave!
‫انتظري، لا أحبّ كيف تبدو غرّتي!‬
Oh...?
‫ماذا؟‬
The sky's so clear! The full moon will look so beautiful tonight!
‫يا لصفاء السماء‬
Tokage Port Hakumai
‫ميناء توكاغي‬ ‫أودون‬ ‫هاكومي‬
Kibi
‫رينغو‬ ‫بلاد وانو‬
Kuri Flower Capital
‫عاصمة الزّهور‬
Ringo
‫كوري‬
Udon
‫كيبي‬
The seasons differ wildly in each region of Wano,
‫تختلف الفصول في كلّ منطقة من مناطق بلاد وانو اختلافًا كبيرًا.‬
Flower Capital
‫عاصمة الزّهور كوري‬
Kuri
‫عاصمة الزّهور كيبي كوري‬
Udon Hakumai
‫هاكومي أودون‬
Kibi Flower Capital
‫كما يختلف الطّقس أيضًا اختلافًا كبيرًا حسب الموقع.‬
At that same moment,
‫نقطة اللّقاء‬
Not a single ship is in sight!
‫لا أرى ولو سفينة واحدة على مدّ البصر!‬
Where are our 4,000 warriors?!
‫أين هم الجنود الأربعة آلاف؟!‬
I am positive we conquered Udon!
‫أنا واثق أنّنا أخضعنا أودون!‬
But there was no one at the mining camp, either.
‫لكن لا يوجد أحد في المنجم أيضًا.‬
This port shows signs of an attack!
‫يبدو أنّ هذا الميناء قد هُوجم.‬
It appears the cat couldn't make it.
‫يبدو أنّ القطّ لم يستطع المجيء.‬
No response on the smail.
‫وكما أنّ لا استجابة من الحلزون.‬
We cannot contact anyone!
‫لا يمكننا...‬
"At twilight on the day of the Fire Festival, at Tokage Port!"
‫«عند الشّفق يوم مهرجان النّار في ميناء توكاغي!»‬
This is the rendezvous port!
‫هذا هو الميناء الموعود.‬
Why has no one arrived?! Just where did they disappear to?
‫لماذا لم يحضر أيّ أحد؟! أين اختفوا يا تُرى؟!‬
It has been but a single day...!
‫مرّ يوم واحد فقط لا غير...‬
What is the meaning of this?!
‫ما الّذي حدث؟!‬
Did something befall them?!
‫هل أصاب الجميع مكروهًا ما؟!‬
Sir Luffy, where are you?!
‫لوفي-دونو، أين أنتم؟!‬
Sir Hyogoro, please respond!
‫هيوغورو-دونو، أجيبوا رجاءً!‬
Inuarashi’s Musketeers!
‫يا فرسان إينواراشي!‬
Sir Law!
‫لاو-دونو! جيبويمون من كيبي!‬
We are Kozuki Oden's retainers!
‫نحن خدم كوزكي أودين!‬
From twenty years ago...
‫قبل عشرين عام مضت...‬
We came from twenty years ago to avenge our lord!
‫أتينا من الماضي قبل عشرين عامًا لنثأر لسيّدنا!‬
We were meant to perish at that time!
‫كان الموت مقدَّرًا لنا آنذاك!‬
So we came to die for a cause!
‫لذا جئنا لنموت فداءً لقضيّتنا!‬
However...
‫إنّما...‬
However, I fear our lives alone are not enough!
‫يتطلّب الأمر أكثر من مجرّد أرواحنا!‬
The enemy has 30,000 warriors! We need your support!
‫تعداد العدوّ 30 ألف جنديّ! نحتاج العون!‬
I am begging you!
‫أتوسّل إليكم!‬
Somebody, please help us!
‫ليساعدنا أحد!‬
Please respond! Anybody!
‫ليجبنا أحد! أتوسّل إليكم!‬
Please help!
‫يكفي يا كينيمون!‬
Look at the sky and sea!
‫انظر إلى السّماء والبحر!‬
Even the heavens have already abandoned us!
‫تخلّت عنّا السّماوات سلفًا!‬
No one is coming to help us!
‫لا يسع أحد مساعدتنا!‬
Something must have happened to everyone...
‫لا بدّ أنّ خطبًا ما قد أصاب الجميع...‬
Dance! Dance!
‫ارقصوا، ارقصوا!‬
It's the annual Fire Festival!
‫إنّه مهرجان النّار السّنويّ!‬
Why don't you let loose and blow off some steam tonight?!
‫لماذا لا تسترخون وتفرغون تّوتّركم اللّيلة؟!‬
There is a small boat over here...
‫ثمّة قارب صغير...‬
We can use it.
‫بوسعنا استعماله.‬
What are you doing, Inuarashi?!
‫ما الّذي تفعله يا إينواراشي؟ توقّف!‬
Let us do this another day, Kin'emon!
‫لنتكفّل بهذا يومًا آخر يا كينيمون!‬
That is a request... I cannot fulfill.
‫هذا ليس خيارًا متاحًا...‬
Master Kin!
‫يا كين-ساما!‬
Let go of me, Shinobu!
‫اتركيني يا شينوبو!‬
Master Kin, we cannot do this tonight!
‫كين-ساما، لا يجوز أن نفعل هذا اللّيلة!‬
We must do it tonight!
‫بل علينا فعله اللّيلة!‬
You know that, Shinobu.
‫تعرفين ذلك حقّ المعرفة يا شينوبو،‬
Onigashima
‫أونيغاشيما‬
It has got to be tonight!
‫لا بدّ أن تكون الليلة!‬
Something had indeed happened the previous night.
‫ثمّة حادثة قد وقعت سلفًا في اللّيلة الماضية.‬
Two Days Ago
‫قبل يومين‬
Turn the clock back two days before the Fire Festival...
‫سنعود للماضي قبل يومين من مهرجان النّار...‬
Amigasa Village
‫قرية‬ ‫أميغاسا‬
I am grateful... truly grateful that they joined us!
‫أنا مسرور... يسرّني كثيرًا انضمامكم لنا.‬
Everyone!
‫أيها الرّفاق،‬
Thank you for all your efforts!
‫شكرًا على ما بذلتموه!‬
Use the remaining time to get into position and prepare.
‫استغِلّوا الوقت المتبقّي للسّفر والاستعداد.‬
Well then...
‫وبعدها...‬
See you at the rendezvous port!
‫سنلتقي في الميناء الموعود!‬
Itachi Port Kuri
‫كوري‬ ‫ميناء‬ ‫إيتاتشي‬
Finish fixing enough ships to carry 5,000 people!
‫حسنًا، أنهوا بناء سفن تكفي لحمل 5000 شخص!‬
– Yes, sir!
‫حاضر.‬
Bring those ships to the port by the appointed time! Can you handle that?
‫أحضروا تلك السّفن إلى الميناء في الوقت الموعود! أيمكنكم ذلك؟‬
Leave it to us, Big Bro Franosuke!
‫اعتمد علينا يا أخي فرانوسكي.‬
Alright!
‫حسنًا!‬
Then, we'll meet up with our friends in Amigasa Village,
‫ميناء إيتاتشي‬ ‫قرية أميغاسا‬ ‫سنلتقي برفاقنا في قرية أميغاسا إذًا،‬
and arrive via the Sunny on the promised day!
‫ونأتي على متن السّاني في اليوم الموعود!‬
We'll leave the rest to you!
‫سنترك الباقي لكم.‬
Yeah! Thanks for helping out!
‫أجل! شكرًا على المساعدة!‬
You guys are top-notch shipwrights!
‫أنتم سفّانون مهرة!‬
Thanks! Let's give those Beast Pirates...
‫شكرًا! فلنقبض على قراصنة الوحوش أولئك...‬
...an ass-kicking they won't forget!
‫ونوسعهم ضربًا يا رجال!‬
Udon No matter how much timber we have, it's never enough! Cut up everything!
‫أودون‬ ‫مهما بلغ مقدار الخشب الموجود بحوزتنا فلن يكفي أبدًا! اقطعوا كلّ شيء!‬
Ocho's group will bring swords and other weapons from Ringo!
‫ستحضر مجموعة أوتشو سيوفًا ونفس الشّيء من رينغو!‬
So...
‫لذلك...‬
We'll craft armor from whatever we have!
‫سنصنع دروعًا من أيّ شيء حولنا!‬
I don't know if they're usable,
‫لا أدري إن كانت قابلة للاستعمال،‬
but we've got tons of stuff that was made for export, even weapons!
‫لكن لدينا كثيرًا من الأسلحة وما إلى ذلك لنأخذها من هنا!‬
Excellent!
‫عظيم!‬
Kibi
‫كيبي‬
We'll draw attention if we travel to the rendezvous point too early.
‫إن ذهبنا إلى نقطة اللّقاء باكرًا جدًّا سنلفت كثيرًا من الانتباه.‬
But...
‫لكن...‬
Habu Port on the morning in question, the shogun's procession will journey from the capital to the port. Flower Capital
‫عاصمة الزّهور‬ ‫ميناء هابو‬ ‫في صباح ذلك اليوم سينطلق موكب الشّوغن من العاصمة إلى الميناء.‬
Once they leave for Onigashima, the Fire Festival will commence in the capital!
‫بمجرّد مغادرته إلى أونيغاشيما سيبدأ مهرجان النّار في العاصمة!‬
No one will pay us any mind!
‫لن نثير انتباه أحدًا!‬
"Two birds..."
‫أودون‬
Udon
‫«عصفوران بحجر...»‬
We had best arrive before twilight.
‫من الأفضل الوصول إلى هنا عند الشفق.‬
Itachi Port Some officials, however, will remain on the mainland!
‫ميناء‬ ‫إيتاتشي‬ ‫لكنّ بعض الضّبّاط سيظلّون في البرّ الرّئيس!‬
Kibi We cannot let them report to Onigashima, so stay alert the whole way!
‫كيبي‬ ‫لا تسمحوا لهم بإرسال تقارير لأونيغاشيما، لذلك ابقوا فطنين طوال الوقت!‬
– Okay!
‫حاضر!‬
Can we really wear these?!
‫أتسمحون لنا بارتداء هذه؟!‬
Wow! It's a samurai helmet! I've gotta show this to Usopp!
‫مذهل! إنّها خوذة ساموراي! كم أتطلع لأُريها أوسوب!‬
We're warriors!
‫نحن محاربون!‬
Your enemy is that ill-famed Kaido.
‫عدوّكم هو كايدو شنيع السّمعة.‬
Are you all prepared?!
‫هل أنتم جاهزون جميعًا؟!‬
Kaido?
‫كايدو؟‬
That loser...
‫ذلك الفاشل...‬
is about to get sliced 'n diced!
‫يوشك أن يُقطّع!‬
It's inconceivable that we would lose!
‫لا أظنّ أنّنا سنخسر بعد الآن!‬
Bring it on!
‫أرونا كلّ ما في جعبتكم!‬
Chobro and the others look so cool!
‫أخي تشو والبقيّة يبدون رائعين!‬
Oh, how cute. Just like bugs.
‫صحيح، كم هذا ظريف.‬
Shouldn't you wear some armor, too?
‫لماذا لا ترتدي درعًا أيضًا؟‬
No, it'll just slow me down.
‫كلّا، سيُبطئ سرعتي فحسب.‬
Wear it.
‫ارتديه...‬
With a bounty that low, you'll be needing it.
‫بما أنّ مكافأتك منخفضة جدًّا!‬
Enma!
‫إنما!‬
You want some of this? I'll snuff the life outta you!
‫أتريد القتال؟! سأقتلك!‬
Try it, you bastard!
‫حاول أن تقتلني أيّها الوغد!‬
What are you morons doing?!
‫أنتما! ما الذي تفعلانه؟!‬
Orochi mentioned it's winter at Onigashima's entrance.
‫قال أوروتشي إنّ الموسم شتاء في مدخل أونيغاشيما.‬
What? It'll be cold?
‫ماذا؟ أسيكون الجوّ باردًا؟‬
What do you mean by "entrance"?
‫ما قصدكِ بـ«مدخل»؟‬
The seasons in Wano vary depending on region.
‫المناطق المختلفة في البرّ الرئيس لبلاد وانو بها مواسم مختلفة.‬
Our fur coats help us withstand the cold.
‫إنّ الفرو يغطّينا، لذلك لا نمانع الطّقس البارد.‬
Inuarashi's Three Musketeers
‫فرسان إينوارايشي الثّلاثة‬
Yeah, for us, the weather is more crucial...
‫صحيح، إنّ الطّقس أهمّ بكثير بالنّسبة لنا...‬
Giovanni Concelot Shishilian
‫جيوفانّي‬ ‫كونسلوت‬ ‫شيشيليان‬
...than the season!
‫من الموسم....‬
There's supposed to be a full moon that night, but it's useless if it's hidden behind the clouds.
‫يُفترض أن يكون القمر بدرًا ذلك اليوم، لكن لا فائدة إن اختفى خلف السحب.‬
That's right!
‫فعلًا.‬
If all the minks can transform like Carrot, that'll be a huge advantage!
‫إن تحوّل كلّ المينك كما فعلت كاروت، فسيساعدنا ذلك كثيرًا!‬
– Garchu!
‫غارتشو!‬
Wanda
‫واندا‬
But we still require luck, even with the Sulong form.
‫لكن تحول سولونغ يعتمد على الحظّ.‬
It's more crucial that Master Nekomamushi and his Guardians make it here.
‫من المهمّ أكثر تواجد السيد نيكوماموشي والحرّاس هنا...‬
What's wrong, Luffy?
‫ما الخطب يا لوفي؟‬
Big Mom is here...
‫بيغ مام هنا...‬
but not Jinbe!
‫لكنّ جينبي لم يصل بعد!‬
Thanks to him, we got away from Big Mom!
‫استطعنا الهروب من بيغ مام بفضله!‬
I'll wait for you in Wano!
‫سننتظرك في بلاد وانو!‬
You better be there!
‫تعال مهما كلّف الأمر!‬
You have my gratitude!
‫شكرًا لك!‬
Jinbe!
‫جينبي!‬
Don't die no matter what!
‫لا تمُت ولو مُتُّ أنا!‬
He settled things and joined our crew!
‫كان عليه الانضمام إلينا بعد اهتمامه بأموره العالقة!‬
We're happy to have him...
‫إنّنا ممتنّون لوجوده معنا...‬
We've still got time... He'll come!
‫ما زال أمامنا وقت...‬
If he's alive, that is.
‫إن كان على قيد الحياة.‬
He's alive! I'm sure!
‫أجل، إنه حيّ!‬
He'll come!
‫وسيأتي!‬
Ebisu Town Outside of the Flower Capital
‫بلدة إبيسو‬ ‫خارج عاصمة‬ ‫الزّهور‬
Hey, everyone! Look at this! The Witching Hour Boy was here!
‫تعالوا يا رفاق! أتى فتى ساعة السحر!‬
But there's no talk of a robbery in the capital!
‫لكن لا حديث عن أي سرقات في العاصمة!‬
There's nobody else who would do something like this!
‫إنّه الشّخص الوحيد القادر على هذا!‬
We can't attend the tomorrow's Fire Festival, but let's use this to purchase drinking water!
‫لا يمكننا المشاركة في مهرجان النّار غدًا لكن لنشرب الماء بهذه.‬
We burned down the mountain bandits' home!
‫أحرقنا جبل قطّاع طرق الجبل!‬
But instead of coming here to seek revenge,
‫لكن بدلًا من السّعي للانتقام،‬
Okobore Town Kuri they continue to steal tons of food from our farm!
‫كوري‬ ‫بلدة‬ ‫أوكوبوري‬ ‫يواصلون سرقة أطنان من الطّعام من مزرعتنا!‬
Headliner Holdem Beast Pirates
‫هولديم‬ ‫شينوتشي بقراصنة الوحوش‬
Do any of you have something to do with this?!
‫أتربطكم علاقة ما بهذا الأمر؟!‬
W-We don't know anything!
‫لا-لا نعرف أيّ شيء!‬
I heard some samurai are preparing for a raid!
‫سمعتُ أنّ السّاموراي يستعدّون لشنّ غارة... أهذا السبب يا ترى؟!‬
If so, we can't let them know!
‫إن كان كذلك، فلن نسمح لهم باكتشافه!‬
What are you swine whispering about?!
‫عمّ تهمسان؟!‬
I will show you where it is!
‫أنا سأرشدك!‬
Otsuru Kin'emon's Wife
‫أوتسورو‬ ‫زوجة كينيمون‬
In exchange, please do not harm anyone.
‫لذلك لا تلحق الأذى بأيّ أحد!‬
M-Miss Otsuru!
‫أو-أوتسورو-سان!‬
You'll show me?
‫سترشدينني؟‬
You know something about this?
‫هل تعرفين أيّ شيء حيال هذا؟‬
You will see once we arrive.
‫سترى بنفسك عندما تصل إلى هناك لكنّ المكان بعيد نوعًا ما...‬
You must need all that food because you have gathered so many allies!
‫لا بدّ أنّك بحاجة لأطنان من الطّعام لأنّ حلفاءك كثر!‬
Right, Kin?
‫صحيح يا كين-سان؟‬
You're here in Wano, right?
‫أنت هنا في بلاد وانو، صحيح؟‬
I was astounded when I saw Kikunojo!
‫فوجئت كثيرًا عندما رأيت كيكونوجو...‬
Kin...
‫كين-سان...‬
Kin, let me handle things here!
‫كين-سان، دعني أتولّى هذا الأمر! سأجذب انتباههم!‬
I will not allow them to search for you!
‫لن أسمح لهم بالبحث عنكم!‬
Kin... Return this country to the Kozuki!
‫كين-سان... استردّ بلاد كوزكي!‬
Stop, Miss Otsuru!
‫توقّفي يا أوتسورو-سان! ليس عليك أن تحمينا!‬
It's okay now!
‫لا بأس الآن! أردنا فقط أن نأكل بقدر ما نشاء قبل موتنا!‬
So you're the culprits!
‫إذًا فأنتم الجناة!‬
Night Before the Great Battle
‫عشيّة‬ ‫المعركة‬ ‫النهائية‬
Red Scabbards...
‫الأغماد...‬
Kuri Beach
‫شاطئ‬ ‫كوري‬
Did you find the ship?
‫هل عثرتم على السّفينة؟‬
Yes.
‫نعم.‬
We found it.
‫وجدناها.‬
You sure about this?
‫لكن هل أنت واثق من هذا؟‬
Don't question me!
‫افعلوا ما أمليه عليكم فحسب!‬
Do it!
‫هيّا!‬
Roger!
‫عُلِم!‬
Mission complete!
‫تمّت المهمّة!‬
I won't let you have your way!
‫لن أدعهم ينجحون في مسعاهم!‬
Next, the bridges!
‫والتّالي، الجسور!‬
Great Kibi-Udon Bridge
‫الجسر الكبير‬ ‫بين كيبي‬ ‫وأودون‬
Detonation complete on the great Kibi-Udon bridge!
‫دُمّر الجسر الكبير بين كيبي وأودون!‬
Destroy them!
‫دمِّروها!‬
Great Kuri-Udon Bridge
‫الجسر الكبير‬ ‫بين كوري وأودون‬
Detonation complete on the great Kuri-Udon bridge!
‫دُمّر الجسر الكبير بين كوري وأودون!‬
Serves them right!
‫يستحقّون ذلك!‬
Great Ringo-Hakumai Bridge
‫الجسر الكبير‬ ‫بين رينغو وهاكوماي‬
Look! The great bridge between the regions...!
‫انظروا! الجسر الكبير بين المناطق قد...‬
Why now?!
‫لماذا فجأة هكذا؟!‬
We cannot get to the other side now!
‫لا نستطيع العبور للجانب الآخر الآن!‬
All that remains is the port!
‫كلّ ما بقي هو الميناء!‬
Itachi Port Kuri
‫كوري‬ ‫ميناء إيتاتشي‬
Lord Orochi! All ships have been destroyed!
‫أوروتشي-ساما! دُمّرت كلّ السّفن!‬
That's fine. We'll rebuild once the dust has settled.
‫لا بأس، سنُعيد بناءها بمجرد انتهاء الأمر.‬
I have yet to see the Red Scabbards or their samurai recruits with my own eyes.
‫ما زلت لم أرَ أحد الأغماد أو جنود السّاموراي الّذين جنّدوهم بأمّ عينيّ بعد.‬
People skipped forward in time from twenty years ago?!
‫أشخاص أتوا من عشرين عام من الماضي؟!‬
How could anyone believe that?!
‫لن يصدق أحد هذا!‬
Maybe if they saw one of their heads...
‫إلاّ إن رأوا إحدى رؤوسهم...‬
No, even if they saw it, they'd never believe it.
‫كلا، فما زال الأمر صعب التّصديق حتّى لو رأوها.‬
And that damn fool, Yasuie, made it sound even more ridiculous!
‫وذلك المغفّل اللّعين ياسويي جعل الأمر يبدو أكثر سخافة!‬
But the information is credible.
‫لكنّ هذه المعلومة موثوقة.‬
The Red Scabbards...
‫الأغماد...‬
still draw breath!
‫أحياءُ يرزقون..!‬
I don't care if my men think I'm crazy.
‫لا يهمني ما إن كان رجالي يظنّونني أتفوّه بالهراء فحسب.‬
I have the authority to take action!
‫فإنني أتمتع بالسّلطة للتصرف كما يجب!‬
I've blocked all possible routes to Tokage Port.
‫أغلقت كلّ الطرقات إلى ميناء توكاغي.‬
Kibi Ringo Kuri Flower Capital Udon Hakumai Tokage Port
‫كيبي‬ ‫رينغو‬ ‫عاصمة الزّهور‬ ‫كوري‬ ‫أودون‬ ‫هاكوماي‬ ‫ميناء توكاغي‬
Four thousand warriors? It's very impressive, recruiting so many.
‫أربعة آلاف جنديّ؟ أحسنتم عملًا بتجنيد كلّ هؤلاء.‬
But none will make it to the port!
‫لكن لن يصل أيّ أحد للميناء!‬
I won't give them even the slimmest chance at taking revenge!
‫لن أمنحهم الفرصة للثّأر!‬
Go to hell, Red Scabbard specters!
‫اللّعنة عليكم يا أشباح الأغماد!‬
Wallow in the despair of isolation and impotence!
‫اغرقوا في يأس العزلة وقلّة الحيلة!‬
Present Day Tokage Port Udon
‫الوقت الحالي‬ ‫ميناء توكاغي‬ ‫أودون‬
Stop, all of you!
‫توقّفوا جميعًا!‬
Taking that small boat is suicide!
‫ركوب ذلك القارب الصّغير انتحار بحدّ ذاته!‬
Let us regroup and begin anew when we get another chance!
‫لنعد جمع صفوفنا ونبدأ من جديد عندما تسنح لنا فرصة أخرى!‬
If we miss this opportunity...
‫إن فوّتنا هذه الفرصة...‬
we will have to wait a whole year.
‫سنضطر للانتظار عامًا كاملًا.‬
But... we cannot hide any longer. They will soon learn how we liberated Udon.
‫لكن ما عاد بمقدورنا الاختباء، سيكتشفون أنّنا استولينا على أودون قريبًا.‬
Kaido's entire army will descend to hunt the rebels,
‫سيأتي جيش كايدو بالكامل لمطاردة المتمرّدين.‬
and we can no longer continue to steal their food.
‫ما عاد بإمكاننا مواصلة سرقة طعامهم أيضًا.‬
Before we departed Kuri, you surely heard what happened.
‫سمعتم عمّا جرى في كوري قبل مغادرتنا بكلّ تأكيد.‬
The people of Okobore Town, who believed in our great struggle...
‫إنّ سكّان بلدة أوكوبوري الّذين آمنوا بمعركتنا الكبيرة...‬
were burned alive.
‫حُرقوا أحياءً.‬
Among them...
‫ومن بينهم كانت...‬
was my wife.
‫زوجتي.‬
Please allow us to go!
‫اسمح لنا بالذهاب رجاءً.‬
No...!
‫لا ينبغي عليكم...‬
Do you want us to flee and live in disgrace?!
‫أتريدنا أن نهرب ونعيش بالعار؟!‬
And what of me...?
‫ماذا عنّي؟‬
We want you to live on with Princess Hiyori!
‫نريدك أن تعيش! أنت ومعك هيروي-ساما!‬
Do not be so selfish!
‫لا تتصرف بأنانية هكذا!‬
Even your father had no support at first!
‫حتّى والدك لم ينعم بدعمٍ في البداية!‬
If we had not met Lord Oden...
‫لو لم نقابل أودين-ساما...‬
...we would not have become samurai, immature as we were.
‫لما كنّا لنصبح ساموراي بما أنّنا كنّا نفتقر للنضج.‬
That is why we want to be...
‫لهذا السّبب نريد أن نظلّ بصفتنا...‬
Lord Oden's samurai retainers... until the very end.
‫ساموراي أودين-ساما حتى النهاية....‬
Do not go!
‫لا تذهبوا!‬
Do not go, Kin'emon!
‫لا تذهب يا كينيمون!‬
Listen, men!
‫اسمعوا يا رجال!‬
This centuries-old policy of national isolation is deeply tied to the Kozuki Clan.
‫هذا الانعزال الوطنيّ الّذي دام لقرون مرتبط تمامًا بالكوزكي...‬
However...
‫وأيضًا‬
the time will eventually come!
‫سيحين الوقت في النّهاية!‬
Before the tides begin to turn worldwide,
‫وقبل أن يبدأ العالم بالتّغيّر،‬
we must open the borders of Wano!
‫افتحوا بلاد وانو!‬
Forty-one years ago, in the Flower Capital...
‫قبل 41 عامًا في عاصمة الزّهور...‬
Kozuki Oden has returned!
‫لقد عاد كوزكي أودين!‬
Hide your wives!
‫أخفوا زوجاتكم!‬
Your daughters, too...!
‫أخفوا بناتكم!‬
Even the livestock!
‫أخفوا ماشيتكم أيضًا!‬
He failed to set sail again!
‫فشل في خوض غمار البحر ثانية!‬
He wants to get out of here that badly?!
‫يريد المغادرة بشدّة هكذا؟!‬
There was a very popular man in the capital.
‫حظي رجلٌ بشعبيّة كبيرة في العاصمة.‬
It is so restrictive!
‫إنها مشبعة بالقيود!‬